Mary Usaji +254 (0) 715 310 306 Mary.usaji@gmail.com

Professional Profile

I am a versatile Web developer with extensive knowledge and experience in Front End development. I create mobile responsive and user-friendly WordPress websites. I am also skilled in HTML, CSS, and JS, to which I frequently apply on-site customization. I work with the most current functionalities and responsive design trends to ensure sites are up to date with the latest Web trends.

Work Experience

2020 - Present Front End Web Developer

Freelancer

- Collaborated with a team of 5 developers to create a Woo Commerce site and Payment App.
- Frequent maintenance of code, website content edits, debugging issues, WordPress themes, and plugin installation.
- Frequent websites and landing pages' implementation from concept through deployment.

2017- 2020 Business Development Executive

Peak Performance International

- Working closely with the IT personnel to come up with new systems that digitized
 most of our products and work processes leading to a 40% increase in market
 coverage.
- Supported in setting up a marketing system and used it to lead a team of 60 affiliate marketers in generating more revenues, leading to a 20% increase in revenue in 3months.
- Participated and actively engaged in strategy meetings with the top management to develop short-term and long-term sales objectives and strategic plans to meet market needs.

2013 - 2017 Sales Assistant Manager

Trouvay and Cauvin Limited

- Meeting with clients on a case-to-case basis to strengthen relationships follow up on previous sales calls, and introduce new ways of working together. This led to a 75% increase in the number of monthly inquiries received from clients
- Assessing market conditions and identifying current and prospective sales opportunities by contacting prospective customers to introduce and promote products, attending trade shows, making direct phone calls, and sending direct emails to clients.
- Assisting and providing technical support to the delivery team by handling shipments resulting in a 50% increase in efficient and timely order delivery to clients.
- Partnered with sales team members and leveraged strong negotiation skills to close tough deals with lucrative clients.

Technologies and Languages

- Languages: Solidity, HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Technologies: Word press, Active Campaign, Teachable, Zoho CRM, Mailchimp

Mobile No: +254 (0) 715 310 306. Email: Mary.usaji@gmail.com

Education and Certifications

Udemy (Online Course) – April 2022 – May 2022

Solidity, Blockchain, and Smart Contract Online Course

FreeCodeCamp – Jan 2022 - Present

Javascript Algorithms and Data Structure

Binance - Feb 2021 - March 2021

Blockchain Development

LinkedIn Courses – *Jul 2020 – Feb 2021*

Software Development

Udemy (Online Course) - *June 2019 – March 2020*

Website Development with HTML5, CSS and JS

Kiriri Women's University of Science and Technology - August 2015 - August 2018

Bachelors of Business Administrations

Graduated with 2nd Class Honors Upper Division

Projects

- Github Link https://github.com/Usajim
- WordPress sites for clients https://peakperformance-int.com || https://moninda.com/ || https://ht

Hobbies

Yoga | Cycling | Volunteering | Reading | Hiking | Dancing | Networking.

Personal details

Languages Proficiency: English (Fluent), French (Basics), Swahili (Fluent)

Referees

1. Romain Lamarque

Director - Africa

Trouvay and Cauvin Limited

+33 6 38 44 35 99

2. James Gitau

Founder/CEO

Peak Performance International

+254 722 760699

Mobile No: +254 (0) 715 310 306. Email: Mary.usaji@gmail.com